Now in this lecture, let's see what are the capabilities that AI agents bring to the table
that help overcome some of the challenges we have seen with large language model based applications
in the last lecture. So we have the same use case from last lecture. We have John who's planning
a two-week scheme vacation. Now let's say we have built an agentic app and this request is sent
to this agentic app or agents as it sometimes called. So before we get into how an agentic
app or agent is going to solve this kind of a user query, you need to remember that agents
are driven by large language model. So the primary brain or thinking capability that agents
possess is powered by large language model. So now as I explain to you how the agentic app is going
to take this user request and solve it, I'm also going to highlight the core capabilities of
AI agents here. Now let's go and see how the agentic app is going to process the user request for
vacation planning. So the first thing once it receives the request, it's going to do task decomposition
and planning which means that it's going to break this complex task into subtasks. So those
subtasks may be check my leave balance, research location for skiing, check whether report, book
a flight, book a hotel. So that's the first core capability that an agentic app brings into
play which is planning or dynamic task planning where it breaks a complex problem into smaller
subtasks. And this is mainly done by the large language model that is driving the agent.
Next the agent will be provided with certain set of tools based on its domain or the purpose for
which it has been built. Now in our case, the domain of this agent is travel planning. So let's see
some of the tools that it can possess. So the second core capability of the AI agents is the tools
and actions that it possesses. So in our case, it could be retrieving the HR data using retrieval
augmented generation solution that might have been integrated with agents. Next, it could search
the web for skiing location. Maybe it will call and whether API where you pass the location
and it will give you the weather data. It could call the hotel.com API and make a booking.
Now you might assume how it's going to execute or what are the kind of tools that it possesses.
So if you see from AWS perspective, what you can do is you can write some custom code in a
lambda function that calls the weather API or that can do the hotel booking. So you can write
any number of lambda functions and integrate that with an agent who will perform certain tasks.
So that's the second core capability of AI agents, which is tools and actions that it
possesses through which it can access any data via the APIs. Okay, now let's look at the third
capability, which is memory for end user interaction. So remember that this agent can make dynamic
decisions. Now let's say he gets two weeks vacation from 15 December to 1 January and he
books the hotel. Now when he's doing the flight booking, he doesn't have any inexpensive flights.
So maybe he needs to replan. So now this agent will go back to the user and say that no flights
are available. Should I replan for first January to 15 January? And if that is so, then it's
going to pass that information and then these tools will be executed again, where he will apply for
a leave. Maybe call weather API and see what's the weather look like and the rebook the hotels.
So there's going to be a lot of data that goes back and forth between the user and the agent.
So all that would be rated in some form of data store, maybe a database in memory store or whatever
service you may choose. And this can be both long term and short term memory and we'll discuss
about the memory in a lot more detail in the subsequent lectures. So the third capability of the
agent is memory where it can store the interaction with the user. So the fourth key capability of
these agents is having some sort of guardrails to prevent toxicity, hallucination of the large
language model that is driving the agent. So maybe the user sends some toxic input and these agents
should be able to detect and block those user requests. So that's the fourth key capability that an
agent should possess, having guardrails for toxicity, hallucination, PI reduction and so on.
And then finally, we have the agent communication. So in this case, you can see we have a single
travel agent that does all of these activities, but there could be scenarios when the user requests
are much more complex. So in that case, you might have specialized agents. So you have one agent
that does the hotel booking, the other agent that does the airline booking and then there will be
some master or supervisor agent that can assign tasks to various agents. So managing multiple agents
by a supervisor agent, managing routing communication between those agents is captured through this
communication capability of AI agents. And we're going to discuss this in a lot more detail in
the next few lectures. Now, if we can quickly summarize, there are five key characteristics of AI agents.
The first one is the ability to do planning by task decomposition, then having memory that stores
the user interaction between the agent and the user. Then you have the tools and actions that an
AI agent can perform, you have the guard rails and then you have the communication.
So before we wrap this lecture, let's quickly take a look at what agentic means and what is a
formal definition of AI agents. So let's first understand what agentic in general means.
It's a term that is used to describe people who are self organizing, proactive, self reflective
and self regulating. And as you will see in future lectures, that is what AI agents are,
they are self organizing, they are proactive and they are self regulating.
Now, let's take a look at what is a formal definition of agentic AI. So NVIDIA describes agentic
AI as sophisticated reasoning and iterative planning to autonomously solve complex multi-step
problem. And as we had seen in the previous example, when we got the request from John on vacation
planning, it involved multiple steps. And that's how the agent broke it down and then solved it.
So there are four things you need to keep in mind when you are looking at agentic AI. First,
it's going to be intelligent autonomous systems. So you don't need to give it explicit directions
on how to solve a problem. So it's going to take a look at the problem, break it down
and then solve it iteratively. So it is autonomous in nature. It can also do the plan, reason,
and act. As we saw in the use case, it took the problem, broke it down into multiple tasks,
and then did some action or executed some tools to get the right answer. It is able to access
enterprise information and we saw how it is able to access the internal HR system to get data
on the leaves. And then finally, it's able to use tools and we discussed about how we can integrate
tools like lambda function within AI agents, which can call weather API, which can call
if hotels.com, API and do some bookings and so on. Okay, so that's pretty much it from this lecture.
I hope you liked this lecture. Thank you.